Hey. Hey. So how was Joan?
瓊安好不好？
Broke up with her. Oh, why?
跟她分手了 為什麼？
Don't tell me. Because of the big nostril thing?
別告訴我 因為鼻孔太大？
They were huge. When she sneezed, bats flew out of them
真的超大！ 她打噴嚏時 會有蝙蝠飛出來
Oh, come on. They were not that huge. I'm telling you, she leaned back. I could
沒那麼大
see her brain. How many perfectly fine women are you going
to reject over the most superficial, insignificant... Oh, hold it, hold it. I mean, I got to side
with Chandler on this one. When I first moved to the city, I went out a couple times with
我剛搬到這裡時 與一個女孩交往
this girl. Really hot, great kisser, but she had the biggest Adam's apple
非常熱情，很會接吻… 但是她的喉結非常大粒！
Drove me nuts. You or me?
真是讓我受不了
I got it. Joey, women don't have Adam's apples
喬伊，女人沒有喉結
You guys are messing with me, right? Yes, we are
你們是在騙我，對不對？
That was a good one. For a second there, I was like, whoa
You name one woman that you broke up with for an actual, real reason
你與哪個女友分手 是因為正當的理由？
Maureen Razzillo. Because she doesn't hate Yanni is not a real
因為她不討厭音樂家雅尼 這不是個正當的理由
reason. Hello, Mr. Heckles
嗨，哈克先生
You're doing it again. We're not doing anything
你們又來了 我們什麼都沒做
You're stomping. It's disturbing my birds. You don't have birds
你們腳步聲太響 嚇到了我的鳥兒 你沒有養鳥
I could have birds. Okay, Mr. Heckles, we'll try to keep it down
我可以養鳥 我們會小聲一點
Thank you. I'm going to rejoin my dinner party
謝謝 我要回去繼續宴客了
All right, bye-bye. Okay, Janice. Janice, you got to give me Janice
好，再見 對了，珍妮絲
That wasn't about being picky. Yeah, we'll give you Janice
我們同意你與珍妮絲分手
I miss Janice, though. Hello, Chandler Bing
但我蠻想珍妮絲的 嗨，錢德寶！
Oh, my God. Oh, Chandler, now
喔，我的天！ 喔，錢德！
Yeah. That's it
對了
Yeah, faster. Stop with the broom
別用掃把了！ 我們沒有製造噪音！
We're not making noise. We won
我們贏了
We did it. Mr. Heckles
我們勝利了！ 哈克先生！
How did this happen? He must have been sweeping
怎麼發生的？ 他大概在掃地
They found a broom in his hand. That's terrible
他們發現他抓著一把掃把
I know. I was sweeping yesterday
昨天我也在掃地
Could have been me. You were sweeping
You never know. Never know
世事難料
Okay. It's very faint, but I can still sense him
很微弱 但我還可以感覺他在大樓裡
in the building. Go into the light, Mr. Heckles
進入光芒中，哈克先生！
Okay, Phoebe. I'm sorry, but sometimes they need help
好了，菲比 對不起 有時候他們需要幫助
Here we go. That's fine
又來了
Go ahead and scoff. You know, there are a lot of things out there
我不相信很多事情…
that I don't believe in, but that doesn't mean they're not true
但這不表示就不是真的
Such as? Like crop circles or the Bermuda Triangle
譬如什麼事？
or evolution. Whoa, whoa, whoa
You don't believe in evolution? No, not really
不真的相信 你不相信進化論？
You don't believe in evolution? I don't know
你不相信進化論？
It's just, you know, monkeys, Darwin. You know, it's a nice story
猴子，達爾文，很好的故事 我只是覺得有點太簡單
I just think it's a little too easy. Too easy?
太簡單？太…
Too... The process of every living thing on this planet
這個星球上的一切生物 經過數千萬年…
evolving over millions of years from single-celled organisms
從單細胞微生物進化而成 而你說太簡單？
is too easy? Yeah, I just don't buy it
對，我不太相信
Excuse me. Evolution is not for you to buy, Phoebe
對不起 進化論不是信不信由你，菲比
Evolution is scientific fact, like the air we breathe
進化論是科學事實 就像我們呼吸的空氣…
like gravity. Oh, okay
Don't get me started on gravity. You, uh, you don't believe in gravity?
別跟我提起地心引力 你不相信地心引力？
Well, it's not so much that, you know, like I don't believe in it
倒不是相不相信的問題
You know, it's just, I don't know. Lately, I get the feeling that
最近我感覺到…
I'm not so much being pulled down as I am being pushed
我不是被吸住，而是被壓著 被壓著…
Uh-oh, it's Isaac Newton and he's pissed. Quick, Pheebs, up on the ceiling
Oh, there she is. And over there, that's the other one
她在那邊，那裡還有另一個
This is Mr. Buddy Boyle, Heckle's attorney. He'd like to talk to you
這是伯弟杜爾 哈克的律師 他想跟你們談談
Okay, what can we do for you? All right, kids, here's the deal
有何貴幹？ 好了，孩子們 事情是這樣的
According to my client's will, he wants to leave all his earthly possessions
他要把他所有財產…
to the, uh, noisy girls in the apartment above mine
Oh! But what about his family? He didn't have any
他的家人呢？ 他沒有家人
Whoa. Okay, so let's talk money
好，讓我們看看有多少錢
All right, there was none. Now, let's talk signing
好，沒有半毛錢 現在，我們來簽字
You be noisy girl number one, you be noisy girl number two
你是一號吵鬧女孩 你是二號吵鬧女孩
I can't believe that this whole time we thought he hated us
我真不相信 我們一直以為他討厭我們
I mean, isn't it amazing how much you can touch someone's life without even knowing it?
真是不可思議 我們能如此感動其他人… 而自己卻不知道？
Would you look at this dump? He hated us. This was his final revenge
看看這個豬窩？！ 他痛恨我們！ 這是他最終的報復！
Ever seen so much crap?
我從來沒看過這麼多廢物！
Actually, I think this apartment sullies the good name of crap
我覺得這間公寓 侮辱了廢物的美名
Ooh, check this out
看看這個
Can I have this?
這個能給我嗎？
How can you not believe in evolution?
你怎麼能不相信進化論？
I don't know. Just, uh, look at this funky shirt
我不知道，就是不相信 看看這條怪襯衫！
Pheebs, I've studied evolution my entire adult life, okay?
菲比 我整個成年都在研究進化論
And I can tell you, we have collected fossils from all over the world
that actually show the evolution of different species, okay?
能夠證明不同物種的進化論
I mean, you can literally see them evolving through time
可以真正看到它們… 透過時間進化
Really? You can actually see it?
真的？可以看得到？
You bet. In the U.S., China, Africa, all over
千真萬確！在美國 中國，非洲，全世界！
See, I didn't know that
這我不知道
Well, there you go
這就是吧
Huh. So now, the real question is
所以真的問題是 誰把化石放在那裡？為什麼？
who put those fossils there and why?
Hey, look at this. My big book of grievances
看看這個！ 我的痛苦之書
Hey, there's me
嘿，這是我！
April 17th. Excessive noise
四月十七日，噪音過度…
Italian guy comes home with a date
意大利佬帶了女伴回家
Hey, Chandler, look. You're in here, too
你也在裡面
April 18th. Excessive noise
四月十八日，噪音過度…
Italian guy's gay roommate brings home dry cleaning
意大利佬帶了女伴回家
Well, that's excellent
真是太好了
Monica, Monica, look at this lamp
看看這盞燈
Is this tacky or what? We have to have this
真是夠俗了 我們一定要帶回去！
Uh, Rach, I think we have enough regular lamps
我們的好檯燈夠多了
What? Oh, come on. I mean, it's not like I'm asking for this girly clock or anything
要這個美女時鐘或什麼的
Which, by the way, I also think is really cool
但我覺得這個也很酷
Look, it doesn't go with any of my stuff
聽著，它與我的東西都不搭配
Well, what about my stuff? You don't have any stuff
那麼我的東西呢？ 你沒有任何東西
This'll be the start of my stuff
Mmm, no
You still think of it as your apartment, don't you?
你還是認為那是你的公寓 對不對？
Mmm, no. Yes, you do
對，你是這麼想
You think of it as your apartment, and I'm just someone who rents a room
你把它想成是你的公寓 我只是租了個房間
Mmm
你支支吾吾的時候 我會為我的新檯燈找個地方放
Okay, while you mmm on that for a while
I'm gonna go find a place for my new lamp
Okay, peeps, see how I'm making these little toys move?
Opposable thumbs
可對立的拇指！
Without evolution, how do you explain opposable thumbs?
可對立的拇指！ 沒有進化論 怎麼發展出可對立的拇指？
Maybe the overlords needed them to steer their spacecrafts
也許外星主宰需要拇指 才能夠駕駛飛碟
Please tell me you're joking
請說你是在開玩笑
Look, can't we just say that you believe in something and I don't?
能不能說你相信進化論 而我不相信？
No, no. No, Pheebs, we can't, okay?
不行，菲比，不能這樣 為什麼不行？
Because it's like math. 1 plus 1 equals 2
I can't stand by and let you think that 1 plus 1
might equal 3 or 4 or yellow
Why not? No, what's that all about?
這是怎麼回事？ 你知道我怎麼想嗎？
What is this obsessive need you have to make everybody agree with you?
為什麼非得每個人都同意你？
You know what? I think maybe it's time
我想你也許應該好好檢視一下 羅斯這個生物了
you put Ross under the microscope
Is there blood coming out of my ears?
我耳朵有沒有流血？
Check it out. Check it out. Heckles' high school yearbook
看看這個 哈克的高中同學錄
Wow, he looks so normal
他看起來好正常！
Yeah, he's even kind of cute
甚至有點可愛
Heckles, you cracked me up in science class
「哈克 你上科學課總是讓我捧腹大笑」
Heckles, you're the funniest kid in school
「哈克 你上科學課總是讓我捧腹大笑」 「你是全校最有趣的學生」
Funniest? Heckles? That's what it says
最有趣？哈克？ 上面是這樣寫的
Wow, Heckles was voted class clown, and so was I
哈克被選為班上的活寶 我也是
He was right. Would you listen to that?
他說得對！ 聽聽那個噪音？
I'd call that excessive
的確是很吵鬧
Whoa. What?
什麼？
Heckles played clarinet in band, and I played clarinet
哈克在樂隊演奏豎笛 我也是
And he was in the scale modelers club, and I was
他參加模型俱樂部 我也…
Well, there was no club, but I sure thought they were cool
雖然我的學校沒有俱樂部 但我覺得模型很酷
So, you're both dorks
Big deal
沒什麼值得大驚小怪
I just think it's weird, you know? Heckles and me
我覺得很怪，哈克與我…
Heckles and me. Me. Me and Heckles
哈克與我，我… 我與哈克
Hey, would you knock it off?
喂，別吵好不好！
Bah!
Have you been here all night?
你整晚都在這裡？
Look at this. Pictures of all the women that Heckles went out with
看看這個
Look what he wrote on them
看看他在上面寫的 「薇安，太高大」
Vivian, too tall
Madge, big gums
「瑪姬，牙齦太多」
Too loud. Too smart
「太大聲」
Makes noise when she eats. This is me
這就是我
This is what I do
這就是我的作法
I'm gonna end up alone, just like he did
我會像他一樣孤獨終老
Chandler, Heckles was a nutcase
哈克是個神經病
Our trains are on the same track, okay?
我們的人生道路方向一樣
Yeah, sure, I'm coming up 30 years behind him, but the stops are all the same
我比他晚了30年 但終點都是一樣
Bittertown. Aloneville. Hermit Junction
愁苦城… 孤獨鎮，隱士村！
Hey, you know what we gotta do?
我們應該離開這裡
We gotta get you outta here. Come on, I'll buy you breakfast. Let's go
我請你吃早餐
Well, what if I never find somebody?
要是我一直找不到伴侶？ 或更糟的，我已經找到了…
Or even worse, what if I already found her, but I dumped her because she pronounces it supposedly?
但我卻因為她說「厚許」 就甩了她？
Chandler, come on
錢德，好啦 你會找到對象的
You're gonna find somebody
How do you know that? How?
你怎麼知道？
I don't know. I'm just trying to help you out
我不知道 我只是想幫你下台
You'll see. You guys are all gonna go off and get married, and I'm gonna end up alone
Will you promise me something?
你能不能答應我一件事？
When you're married, will you invite me over for holidays?
你結婚後 過節時能不能請我去玩？
I mean, I don't know what we're gonna be doing
我不知道我們會怎麼樣
I mean, what if we're over at her folks' place?
要是我與妻子 到我岳父母那裡過節呢？
Yeah, I understand
我瞭解
You can come over and watch the Super Bowl
你可以過來看超級杯
Every year, all right?
每一年都來，怎麼樣？
You know what?
我不要像這樣子下場！
I'm not gonna end up like this. I'll see you, man
待會見，兄弟
Jeez
Supposedly
Did they go to the zoo?
他們去動物園了嗎？
Supposedly
Hi. It's me
嗨，是我
Oh. My. God
我的天！
Janice? You called Janice?
珍妮絲？你打給珍妮絲？
Yes, Janice. Why is that so difficult for you to comprehend?
是的，珍妮絲
You remember Janice, right?
你還記得珍妮絲吧？
Yes. She was smart. She was pretty
是啊，她很聰明，很漂亮 而且很關心我
And she honestly cared about me
Janice is my last chance to have somebody
珍妮絲是我的最後一個希望
Hello
Oh. My. God
喔，天啊！
Jeez. Look how fat she got
她真是胖了不少
Hey. It's everybody
嗨，大家都在這裡！ 嗨，珍妮絲
Janice, you're
珍妮絲，你…
Yes, I am
是的，我有了
Is it?
Is it yours? Ha! You wish, Chandler Bing
沒那麼好的事，錢德寶！
You are looking at a married lady now
我已經是少奶奶了
Oh
要我錯過看到你的表情？ 才不要！
Congratulations
Oh, sweetie. I'm sorry
甜心，真抱歉
I couldn't wait for you forever
You couldn't have told me about this over the phone?
你不能在電話上告訴我嗎？
And what? Miss the expression on your face?
要我錯過看到你的表情？ 才不要！
Oh, no. Janice likes to have her fun
珍妮絲喜歡樂子！
Hey, Rach. You know what we haven't played in a while?
你知道我們很久沒玩什麼嗎？
What?
要我錯過看到你的表情？ 才不要！
Hide the Lamp
藏起檯燈
Monica, let it go
摩妮卡，算了吧
Did you know I was allergic to shellfish?
你知道我對貝類過敏嗎？
Well, then, you'll just have to eat the other lamps
那麼你必須吃其他的檯燈
Uh-oh. It's Scary Scientist Man
可怕的科學家來了
Okay, Phoebe. This is it
菲比，這些就是了
In this briefcase, I carry actual scientific facts
在這個手提箱中 我帶來了真正的科學證據
A briefcase of facts, if you will
可算是整個提箱的證據
Some of these fossils are over 200 million years old
其中有些化石超過2億年老
Okay, look. Before you even start
我要先告訴你 我並不否定進化論
I'm not denying evolution, okay?
I'm just saying that it's one of the possibilities
It's the only possibility, Phoebe
進化論是唯一的可能
Okay. Ross, could you just open your mind like this much?
羅斯 你能不能稍稍敞開心胸？
Okay? Now, wasn't there a time
when the brightest minds in the world believed that the Earth was flat?
And up until, like, what, 50 years ago
you all thought the atom was the smallest thing
until you split it open and this, like, whole mess of crap came out
後來科學家擊碎了原子 於是產生了各種玩意…
Now, are you telling me
難道你是如此自大…
that you are so unbelievably arrogant
that you can't admit that there's a teeny tiny possibility
無法承認有一點點的可能…
that you could be wrong about this?
你們科學家也許會犯錯？
There might be
是有一點點…
a teeny
無法承認有一點點的可能…
tiny
possibility
無法承認有一點點的可能…
I can't believe you caved
我真不相信你屈服了
What?
怎麼了？
You just abandoned your whole belief system
I mean, before, I didn't agree with you
but at least I respected you
How are you going to go into work tomorrow?
How are you going to face the other science guys?
How are you going to face yourself?
That was fun. So who's hungry?
I am
我餓了
Okay, all right
It was an accident, I swear
這是意外，我發誓
All right, I was putting on my jacket and the thing
我正在穿外套 檯燈就破了
and the lamp and it broke
Oh, please, Monica, you've always hated my lamp
拜託，摩妮卡！ 你痛恨我的檯燈！
And now, all of a sudden
突然間 它就奇跡似地破了？
it's just magically, it's just broken?
Phoebe, tell her
菲比，告訴她
Okay, I didn't see it because I was putting on my jacket
我沒看到 因為我正在穿外套
but I want to believe you
但我想要相信你
Hey, Chandler
嗨，錢德 摩妮卡打破了我的貝殼檯燈
Monica just broke my seashell lamp
Neat. I'm going to die alone
真好
Okay, you win
好，算你贏
Chandler, you are not going to die alone
錢德，你不會死得孤苦伶仃
Janice was my safety net, okay?
本來珍妮絲是我的安全保障
And now I have to get a snake
現在我必須去養一條蛇了
Uh-huh. Why is that?
為什麼？
If I'm going to be an old, lonely man
I'm going to need a thing, you know, a hook
有個依靠
Like that guy on the subway who eats his own face
就像地鐵上那個吃自己臉的人
So I figure I'll be Crazy Man with a Snake
我會成為 「養蛇的瘋老頭」
You know, Crazy Snake Man
養蛇瘋子
Then I'll get more snakes, call them my babies
然後我會養更多蛇 當成我的子女
kids won't walk past my place, they will run
Run away from Crazy Snake Man
養蛇瘋子
No, shop
You've got to get over this, okay?
你必須想開一點
You're not going to end up alone
Of course I am
I reject anyone who's crazy enough to actually go out with me
我甩掉了所有 笨得願意跟我交往的女孩
and then I bitch about the fact that there aren't any great women out there
然後我抱怨找不到好女孩
Chandler, you have just described
我們所交往的男人…
virtually every man that we have ever gone out with
就跟你所描述的一樣
Yeah
You are not a freak. You're a guy
你沒什麼問題 你只是個平常人
Yeah, honey, she's right
她說得對
I mean, you all do it
This one guy stopped seeing me because his cat didn't like me
Or this guy dumped me because I fell asleep during Spinal Tap
You fell asleep during Spinal Tap?
Oh, oh, that Teddy-what's-his-name in high school
who stopped seeing you because he thought you were too fat
He told me it was because he didn't have time for me because of the play
That's what I said
Anyway, my point being, you are no different than the rest of them
Wait a minute, wait a minute. Yes, he is
等一下，等一下 他是不一樣
You are totally different
你其實很不一樣
In a bad way?
很糟糕嗎？
No, honey, in a wonderful way. You know what you want now
不，甜心，是很好的不一樣 現在你知道你要什麼了
Most guys don't even have a clue
大多數男人根本不知道
You are ready to take risks. You're ready to be vulnerable and intimate with someone
你準備好接受風險了 準備好接受傷害，與人親近
Yeah, you're not going to end up alone
你不會孤苦伶仃的
Chandler, you called Janice
你打電話給珍妮絲 這證明你希望與人廝守終生！
That's how much you wanted to be with someone
You've made it. You're there
你已經改變了！ 你不一樣了！
You are ready to make a commitment
你準備好做出承諾了！
Whoa, don't know about that
但是自己卻不知道！
Whoa, what you got there?
你拿了什麼？
Something else that's not yours that you can break?
不是你的東西 而你想要打破？
No
但是自己卻不知道！
I know you like this and I want you to have it
我知道你喜歡這個 我也要你收下它
I think it will look good in our apartment
Thank you
謝謝
That's fine
沒關係
Hey
Well, you will all be pleased to know that I have a date tomorrow night
This woman, Allison, from work, she is great
我的同事愛莉森 人很不錯
She's pretty. She's smart
她又漂亮又聰明 我一直…
And I've been holding off asking her out in the past
沒有約她出來 因為她有一個…
because she has a unusually large head
不尋常的大頭！
But I'm not going to let that stuff hang me up anymore
但我不要讓這種事情阻止我
Look at me. I'm growing
看看我，我成熟了
Hey, you can't recycle yearbooks, can you?
同學錄有沒有回收？
I'll take that
那個給我
You want his yearbook?
你要他的同學錄？
Yeah. Some people said some nice things about him
有人說了他的好話 應該留下來
You think somebody should have it?
Oh, gosh, this is so weird
這真的很奇怪
I mean, his whole life was in this apartment and now it's gone
他整個生命都在這公寓度過 現在人去樓空
You know, I think it would be nice if we just took a few moments
我想我們應該為 哈克先生默哀一會兒
from Mr. Heckles
I mean, he was kind of a pain. He was
他是個麻煩人物 但他是個人物
But he was a person
What?
You're all going to hell
你們全都會下地獄
It's really not that big
其實沒有那麼大！
Taking that with you, huh?
你要拿那個走吧？ 沒錯
Oh, yeah
Hey, you coming?
你來嗎？
Yeah, in a second
等一下
Goodbye, Mr. Heckles
再見，哈克先生
We'll try to keep it down
我們會安靜點
Oh, my major was totally useless
我完全學非所用
I mean, how often do you look in the classifieds and see philosopher wanted?
報紙上什麼時候看得到 「徵求哲學家」？
Sure
對啊
My God, that's a big head
天啊，那真是個大頭！
It didn't look this big in the office
在辦公室看起來沒這麼大 也許是因為燈光
Maybe it's the lighting
My head must look like a golf ball at work
我的頭在公司 一定像個高爾夫球那麼小
All right, don't get hung up on it
不要想了 快列出你喜歡她的五件事
Quick, quick, list five things you like about her
Nice smile, good dresser, big head, big head, big head
笑容很美，衣著高雅 大頭，大頭，還是大頭！